Guide to the Office of University Life records, 1970-1999 UA.09.08.0003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Office of University Life records
1970-1999
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Office of University Life
UA.09.08.0003
3.5 Linear Feet
The Office of University Life was created in the 1993 reorganization of the Division of Student Affairs and is responsible for cultural programming and scheduling of cultural facilities. It is also responsible for the oversight and advising of student organizations, including student government and the University Union. It was previously known as the Office of Cultural Affairs. This collection includes files on events, correspondence, memoranda and files created by Associate Dean of University Life, Richard Cox. The collection also contains files associated with the Greek Life Task Force, 1993-1994, which was established by the Student Affairs Board of Trustees Committee to examine the interaction between greek organizations and student life at Duke.
Historical note
The Office of University Life was created in the 1993 reorganization of the Division of Student Affairs and is responsible for cultural programming and scheduling of cultural facilities. It is also responsible for the oversight and advising of student organizations, including student government and the University Union. It was previously known as the Office of Cultural Affairs.
Collection Overview
This collection includes files on events, correspondence, memoranda and files created by Associate Dean of University Life, Richard Cox. The collection also contains files associated with the Greek Life Task Force, 1993-1994, which was established by the Student Affairs Board of Trustees Committee to examine the interaction between greek organizations and student life at Duke.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Office of University Life records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in July, 1995; March, 1996; July, 1996.
Conditions Governing Access
Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been in existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
Cox, Richard; Duke University--Administration; Duke University--Students--Social life and customs; Duke University. Office of Cultural Affairs; Duke University. Board of Trustees; Duke University. Greek Life Task Force
- Richard Cox papers, 1971-1995; 1
  - Hospital Walk-through Policy, 1989-1993 (Box 1)
  - Hospital Walk-through Policy, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Beta Phi Zeta Incident/Charter Revocation, 1982 March-August (Box 1)
  - Bill Griffith Weekend Expenses, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Old Trinity Club, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - John Zeidman Lectureship Fund, 1983-1988 (Box 1)
  - Campus Community Council, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Psychological Services/CAPS, 1991-1994 (Box 1)
  - Psychological Services/CAPS, 1974-1988 (Box 1)
  - Career Development Center, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
  - Corey Fund, Experiential Learning Endowment, 1989-1994 (Box 1)
  - Cultural Affairs, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
  - East Campus, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
  - Final Report of the Residential Life Task Force, 1980 April (Box 1)
  - East Campus Council, 1989-1993 (Box 1)
  - East Campus Council, 1980-1988 (Box 1)
  - Freshman Year Experience Conference, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Freshman Year Programs, 1989-1992 (Box 1)
  - Health Administration, Trent Drive Hall, 1988-1991 (Box 1)
  - Articles, Clips, etc.: Duke's Vision, 1991 (Box 1)
  - International Student Living, 1982-1992 (Box 1)
  - Job Enhancement Program, 1983-1991 (Box 1)
  - Kangaroo Publications, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Leadership Program, 1981-1992 (Box 1)
  - Lubans Inquiries, 1989-1992 (Box 1)
  - Men's Task Force, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Minority Affairs, 1975-1993 (Box 1)
  - Multi-Cultural Task Force, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
  - Noise Policy, 1978-1993 (Box 1)
  - Old Trinity Club, 1977-1982 (Box 1)
  - Open Society Scholar's Fund, 1994, January (Box 1)
  - Pan-Hellenic, 1989-1994 (Box 1)
  - President's Office, 1986-1992 (Box 1)
  - Provost's Office, 1986-1994 (Box 1)
  - Articles: Publications Board, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
  - Religious Life, 1984-1993 (Box 1)
  - Committee on Resources, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - University Schedule Committee, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
  - SCOPE Program, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Southgate Gym, 1983-1993 (Box 1)
  - Student Activities, 1981-1993 (Box 2)
  - Student Life, 1983-1990 (Box 2)
  - Student Affairs, 1989-1995 (Box 2)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted until 2020.
  - Student Affairs, 1978-1988 (Box 2)
  - Student Affairs Retreats, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Student Affairs Leadership Assistance Program, 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - Trinity College, 1989-1995 (Box 2)
  - UPS Committee, 1980-1993 (Box 2)
  - University Counsel, 1981-1987 (Box 2)
  - University Craft Center, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - General File, 1987-1995 (Box 2)
  - Fresco Audio Productions, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - WXDU Station, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Women's Center, 1988-1993 (Box 2)
  - Women's Studies Living Space, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Zeidman Fund, 1982-1985 (Box 2)
  - Zeidman Fund, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Freewater, Jabberwocky, Residential Life Report, 1974-1988 (Box 2)
  - Duke Parents' Letter Vol. 4 No. 4, 1987 (Box 2)
- Artists and Programs, 1970-1999; 2
  - Artsfare, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Artsfare, 1981-1984 (Box 2)
  - Broadway at Duke Playbills, 1973-1982 (Box 2)
  - Duke Artists Series, 1970-1976 (Box 2)
  - Duke Artists Series, 1976-1980 (Box 2)
  - Duke Artists Series, 1980-1984 (Box 2)
  - Ella Fountain Pratt Gala, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Wilhelmenia Fernandez (Soprano), 1984 (Box 2)
  - Artists at Duke, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Programs, 1979-1986 (Box 2)
  - Arts at Duke, 1979-1986 (Box 2)
  - American Recording Orchestra, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Napoleon, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Abelard and Heloise, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Orientation, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Summer Festival of the Arts, 1994-1996 (Box 3)
    Restricted until 2021.
  - Calendar of Events, 1993-1997 (Box 3)
    Restricted until 2022.
  - Chamber Arts Society, 1994-1999 (Box 3)
    Restricted until 2024.
- Greek Life Task Force, 1989-1995; 3
  - Task Force on Greek Life Report, 1994 April (Box 3)
  - Student Affairs Trustee Committee Meeting, 1994 May (Box 4)
    Restricted until 2044.
  - Final Report Greek Taskforce, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Drafts and Attachments, 1994; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Alcohol, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Articles: Elsewhere, 1989-1993 (Box 3)
  - Fraternities and Intellectualism, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Board of Trustees, Quality of Life, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Calendar of Meetings, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Changes, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Board of Trustees, Dean White, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Fraternity Insurance Group Policy, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Focus Group, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Dickerson, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Ground Rules, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Hazing, 1994 (Box 3)
  - History at Duke, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Housing, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Greek Reports, 1992-1994 (Box 3)
  - Let Duke be Duke, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Minutes and Attachments, 1992-1994 (Box 3)
  - Membership, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Invoices, 1994 January (Box 3)
  - Name Cards, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Nannerl Keohane, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Number of Frats, Sororities, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Pan-Hellenic, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Party Policy, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Dartmouth, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Personal Notes, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Points for Discussion, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Price Speech, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Reservable Spaces, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Rima's Notes, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Sophomore Rush Proposal, B. Ward, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Residential Life Task Force, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Town Meeting, 1994 January (Box 3)
  - William H. Williamson, We Work Hard, We Play Hard, 1993 April (Box 3)
  - Minutes and Drafts, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Notes and Memoranda, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Articles and Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 3)